Episode 5
"Golden Freesia"
Saint of Bolmern
Grace Mattilas
Thank you for making the long journey here.
I welcome you, Grace.
S... S...
Saint Philia!
Saint Philia Adenauer!
I'm so honored to meet you!
My name is Grace Mattilas!
Getting to study under the greatest
saint of all time is like a dream to me!
I-Is it?
The Too-Perfect Saint: Tossed Aside
by My Fiancé and Sold to Another Kingdom
Several Days Earlier
Miss Philia, I've been wanting to ask you...
Would you like to try being a tutor?
A tutor?
Have you heard of the Mattilas family?
The Mattilas family?
Of the Kingdom of Bolmern?
That's them.
They've produced saints
for Bolmern for generations,
and they have deep ties
to the royal family there.
The Elcrantz family, which has
produced Parnacorta's saints,
originated as a branch
of the Mattilas line as well.
Continent of Sedelgard
Kingdom of Ashbrugge
Kingdom of Murasame
Kingdom of Bolmern
Kingdom of Gyptia
Kingdom of Parnacorta
Kingdom of Dalbert
Kingdom of Alectron
Kingdom of Girtonia
Because our countries are so close,
we have a lot of interaction
with the Mattilas family.
And recently, they sent us a request
to learn purification magic from you.
They'd like to send their fourth
daughter, Grace, to study here.
I see.
In that case...
Utmost apologies for startling you.
Grace's Personal Butler
Arnold
Lady Grace is a great fan of yours.
She applies herself diligently every day
in hopes of becoming a saint like you.
Please overlook her indiscretions.
R-Right.
Arnold! I told you that I wanted to tell
her what a big fan I was myself!
Forgive me.
Saint Philia appeared
stunned by your intensity.
Correct
Saint Philia, I know I'm quite inexperienced,
but please teach me all you can!
It appears things are going to be lively
at the mansion for the foreseeable future.
Saint Philia.
Are you certain about this?
To teach the Great Purification Circle
to someone from another kingdom...
It's not as if it's a closely guarded secret.
But it does take knowledge of ancient rituals,
and not everyone can perform them.
Indeed, the Great Purification Circle
doesn't require particular talent.
What it does require
are knowledge and perception.
As the former goes, one must
study the ancient language.
Mia can't use the Great Purification Circle
because she doesn't know the required tongue.
If only I could at least teach
her the ancient language...
It seems the Mattilas family incorporates
ancient language lessons into their training,
so if Grace knows enough,
she may be able to pick up
the Great Purification Circle quickly.
I would now like to begin
our ancient ritual class.
SO
EXCITED
I can't wait!
You need two things
to perform ancient rituals:
knowledge and perception.
You must know the ancient language,
which I believe you've already
studied to some degree.
Then there's perception.
Let's practice perceiving the
natural magic power necessary
to use ancient rituals, known as mana.
Yes, ma'am!
But what is this "mana"?
I've never heard of it before...
Let me see.
Typically, when we cast spells,
we're using the magic power inside of us.
This is known as od.
By contrast, magic power that comes
from the natural world is called mana.
Many ancient rituals, like the Great
Purification Circle, are so massive in scale
that it would be difficult to
perform them with our magic alone.
We use mana to fill in the gaps.
That is why the first challenge
is learning how to perceive mana.
I see!
Stand outside and feel the sunlight.
Listen to the rustling of the plants.
If you put yourself into a trance while
feeling the power of nature through your body,
I believe it will be easier
to get the sense of it.
I'll try!
Huuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuh?
Hrmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm...
This reminds me of my own training.
Saint Philia!
I can't sense the mana at all!
Sad
I can tell there's power in nature,
but that's about all...
That will do for now.
That faint sensation means you're
capable of perceiving mana.
Hone that sense and, in time, you'll
be able to interact with it as well.
As for how to push you further...
Let me think.
Come, light!
Ancient Ritual
Robe of Light
This shining light is mana.
I thought it might be easier
to observe with a visual element.
Saint Philia, you look beautiful.
You're like an angel.
I'm sure you're exaggerating.
What's going on here?
It's like she's hanging on my every word.
Why would someone from another kingdom
whom I've never met before...
To be honest...
Your books, Treatises on Sainthood...
They're my personal bible!
Treatises on Sainthood
By Philia Adenauer
Now on sale continent-wide
What do you say, Saint Philia?
I forgot I'd published books.
I believe the people misunderstand
much of what sainthood entails.
Let's do it!
Editor
I turned the idea down a few times because it
seemed irrelevant to my saintly duties,
I think publishing your
writings is a great idea!
What do you think? Let's do it!
but I eventually acquiesced.
That was just a collection of things
I've learned in my time as a saint
and my general research.
Nothing praiseworthy.
No, you're wrong!
Your books kept me going in my darkest hour!
I'm the fourth daughter in a family of
saints, with no exceptional talent...
I was only able to stay strong
through my fierce training
because I read Treatises on Sainthood
and was touched by its teachings!
I wanted to be just like you someday!
It was clear to me
just from reading your work.
There was none the authorial judgment
that usually slips into books.
It revealed an impartial heart,
almost awkwardly dedicated to the craft.
I could hardly believe
someone like you existed.
And so I've always wanted
to meet you and tell you...
Thank you!
For becoming a saint,
for writing those books...
Thank you so much.
You saved me.
The arrogance of publishing this drivel!
Does your shamelessness know no bounds?!
Treatises on Sainthood?!
It's nothing but boasting
about your accomplishments!
We're ceasing its publication at once.
My books are no longer circulated in Girtonia.
The world I lived in rejected
me at every turn...
so I began to believe that was normal.
I came to regret ever writing anything.
But...
I see now.
The world I lived in was so small, wasn't it?
The Too-Perfect Saint: Tossed Aside
by My Fiancé and Sold to Another Kingdom
Let's take a break now.
Yes, ma'am!
Saint Philia, have you ever
instructed anyone before me?
No. You're the first.
I'm your first student?!
How wonderful!
Your explanations are so easy to understand!
And when you praise me,
it gives me so much motivation!
Does it?
It does!
I feel like Lena said something similar.
I'm just imitating my own teacher, though.
The person who taught you?!
Would that be the previous saint
of Girtonia, then?
Yes.
Her name is Hildegard Adenauer.
She's my father's elder sister.
That is, my paternal aunt.
What was she like?
I mean, I got used to it...
She was very strict.
Saint Philia, your eyes have glazed over!
"Unsparing" is the word I might use.
She cast me on a mountain in winter
to teach me to survive by myself.
She buried me in the desert all on my own.
She had me lie on beds of needles
to practice my magic control.
It was hard.
That feels like it goes way beyond "hard"!
But in that case, is there a reason
she was that hard on you?
I mean, whether someone's mean
or kind, likes you or hates you,
there's always a reason.
A reason?
I'm sorry, Philia.
You haven't done anything wrong.
But I've always had a bad
relationship with your parents,
and you look so much like
me when I was younger...
It's not your fault they hate you.
That's why I've tried hard
to make you strong.
So that you can bounce back
from anything life throws at you.
That's right.
My teacher was always concerned for me.
To think I'd only realized something so
important after leaving the kingdom...
Forgive me, my mentor.
Lena.
Yes?
Why does the main character agree
to elope here, even though it's wrong?
Well, that's because...
her desire to do it wins out in the end!
Is that how it works?
It certainly is!
I'm sorry to ask you so many questions.
I don't mind!
I'm glad to be able to chat
with someone about it.
Saint Philia.
A letter from Himari.
"Delivery complete"
Now, regarding tomorrow...
The carriage has been arranged.
Saint Philia, are you going somewhere?
Yes.
Grace wants to visit Elizabeth's grave.
My dear Liz...
She passed a few months ago, didn't she?
Yes. About three months ago.
Liz... Elizabeth... was my cousin.
She was born with a frail constitution,
so my father was always worried about her.
I came to Parnacorta to see her rather often.
I see.
Philia?
And...
Liz?
No...
Grace, was it?
Indeed, I am Grace Mattilas.
You visit Elizabeth's grave
as well, Prince Reichardt?
Yes.
She and I were previously engaged.
She always loved these flowers...
Golden freesia.
I longed to give her finer presents,
but she told me that the scent of
these flowers reminded her of me.
I never knew what to say to that.
I have a hard time reading
emotions, but even I can tell...
He's still in love with Elizabeth.
That was quite a surprise.
I never thought I'd get
to meet Prince Reichardt.
I've heard his duties keep him terribly busy.
Yes.
I guess people can truly love that deeply.
I've never been loved before.
I'm still not even really sure what love is.
It's only natural that I wouldn't understand.
Wait...
All this time, I've been trying
to earn the love of others.
Have I ever tried to love anyone?
Saint Philia! Do you have a minute?
I do.
Sorry, but could you make
this delivery for me?
Hey, Miss Philia!
Prince Osvalt...
Fancy running into you!
What brings you all the way out here?
Lena asked me to bring this.
Goodbye.
Mission Complete
That was fast!
Wait, wait, wait a minute!
There's enough for two here.
Care to join me?
Wow, these are good!
What a beautiful garden.
He tends it all by himself,
without any help...
But why?
Wondering why I do all this?
Yeah, makes sense.
I'm not interested in the throne.
But despite how I feel,
the nobles around me
insisted on forming factions
and tried to advocate for my claim.
I couldn't stand it.
I love this kingdom, and I love my family.
So I decided to play the layabout son
not worth playing politics over.
And that was that.
He's not a prince first.
He's a kind soul who loves his family.
Yesterday, I ran into Prince
Reichardt at the cemetery.
I see.
He was deeply in love with Elizabeth.
Seeing my straitlaced brother
head over heels for a girl...
It was really something.
He said that protecting the saint
was the duty of a worthy king.
That was a surprise.
But he couldn't save her.
"What kind of future king can't
protect the woman he loves?"
As if to punish himself, he's thrown
himself tirelessly into his duties.
But surely there's no reason to...
Yeah, it's a sad thing.
But I know that sometimes
you need time to feel sad.
It's just frustrating that all I can do
is watch until his wounds heal.
He really could use a hobby like mine!
A hobby?
When I decided to play the layabout son,
I spent some time thinking
about what I should do.
I figured if I was picking up a hobby,
it shouldn't just be for me...
I wanted it to bring joy
to the folks around me, too.
The idea of something I do
making other people happy...
That's as delightful as it gets.
What about you, Miss Philia?
Me?
Ever felt that way?
I've never...
ever...
Thank you, Big Sister!
Thank you!
Saint Philia, thank you so much!
I...
I've always thought that, as a saint,
I should abstain from personal desires
and instead dedicate myself
to the prosperity of our kingdom.
But in the end, I was just trying
to make my parents happy.
I thought if I couldn't make them happy,
acknowledge me, love me...
There would be no point to any of it.
That was the only thing I could see.
But there were plenty of people around
me whom I was making happy.
I'm only just realizing that.
Miss Philia...
You've done great!
If your parents won't acknowledge you,
I'll acknowledge all
you've done in their stead.
Guess that's kinda presumptuous, huh?
No...
Not at all.
I've always... always...
wanted to hear those words.
Thank you so much.
And that's why it's necessary.
I see.
So the mistress is attempting to perceive
this "mana" which you describe?
Hey, Arnold.
Are you interested in ancient rituals now?
No.
But your father has asked me to report
on his darling daughter's progress.
Father...
Darn it!
Tell him I'm working hard to help Bolmern!
I'm fifteen years old already!
Tell him to stop treating me like
a little child all the time!
I'd also like to help the people of
this kingdom who've been so kind to me.
I'm a saint now, so I'm working really,
really hard on my own!
I'd also like to help...?
Wait. In ancient rituals...
Pardon me. That will be all
for our lesson today.
Brother.
Why have you summoned me so suddenly?
Right.
This letter just arrived.
Wait, is this some kind of joke?
No. For reasons unknown,
the Kingdom of Girtonia...
has requested that we return Saint Philia.
The Too-Perfect Saint: Tossed Aside by
My Fiancé and Sold to Another Kingdom.
Next time, episode 6:
Next Time
Episode 6
"Reason and Emotion"
"Reason and Emotion."